Guide to the Lee S. Shulman Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Lee S. Shulman papers
1965-2006
SC0905
Shulman, Lee S.
70.5 Linear feet
Papers pertain to his teaching and research career at Michigan State and Stanford; included are correspondence, articles, speeches, case study files, course files, project files, and other materials.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Access: collection is closed until processing is completed.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Lee Shulman, professor emeritus of education at Stanford, has been president of the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching since 1997. He earned his doctorate in educational psychology from the University of Chicago in 1963 and was on the faculty of Michigan State University from 1964 until he came to Stanford in 1982.
Description of the Collection
Papers pertain to his teaching and research career at Michigan State and Stanford; included are correspondence, articles, speeches, case study files, course files, project files, and other materials.
Access Terms
Shulman, Lee S.; Stanford University. Graduate School of Education. -- General subdivision--Faculty.;; Education--Research--United States.; Learning.; Teaching.
Collection Contents
- CORRESPONDENCE/DATEBOOKS, Series 1
  - 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - M-R, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - A, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - B, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - C, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - D, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - E, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - F, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - G, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - H, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - I-J, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Harry Judge visit, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - K, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - L, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - M, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - N, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - O-P, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Q-R, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Rosenshine, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - S, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - T, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - U-V, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - W-Z, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Shulman/Robert Levin correspondence, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - correspondence re. Grawemeyer award, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- PAPERS/SPEECHES, Series 2
  - "Doubling the Square," Shulman (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Problem Solving," Shulman [ca. early 1960's] (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "An Experimental Study of Patterns of Inquiry," Basic and Applied Research Proposal, Shulman, Feb. and August, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dissertation Abstract: "Seeking Styles and Individual Differences in Patterns of Inquiry," Shulman (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Seeking Styles and Individual Differences in Patterns of Inquiry," Shulman [ca. 1965] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Reconstruction in Educational Research," as presented at the Research Conference on Racial Desegregation and Integration in Public Education, Shulman, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Perspectives on the Psychology of Learning and the Teaching of Mathematics," Shulman, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Review of "Modes of Thinking in Young Children," Shulman, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Reconstruction of Educational Research," Shulman, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "The Study of Individual Inquiry Behavior," Shulman [ca. 1967] (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Inquiry, Computers, and Medical Education," Shulman (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Psychological Controversies in the Teaching of Science and Mathematics," Shulman, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Lack of Formal Schooling and the Acquisition of Conservation," Mermelstein and Shulman, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Multiple Measurement of Self-Concept," Shulman [ca. 1968] (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Learning and Instruction in Chicago Inner-City Schools," Farquhar and Shulman, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Negro-White Differences in Employability, Self-Concept, and Related Measures Among Adolescents classified as Mentally Handicapped," Shulman, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "On the Application of Primary Process Thinking to the Naming of Second-Order Factors," Shulman, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Cognitive Learning and the Educational Process," Shulman [ca. 1970] (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Psychology and Mathematics Education," Shulman [ca. 1970] (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Methods and Theory In the Study of Medical Inquiry," Elstein, Kagan, Shulman, Jason, Loupe, [1972] (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Evaluation Design: Model Neighborhood Elementary School Individualized Learning Program," Shulman, Lezotte, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Evaluation Design: Model Neighborhood Elementary School Individualized Learning Program: Elaboration of Design III," Shulman, Lezotte, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "The Analysis and Teaching of Medical Problem-Solving: A Proposal for Continued Support," Shulman and Elstein, [ca. 1972] (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Guggenheim Foundation: report of fellowship, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Model Neighborhood Elementary School Individualized Learning Program," Interim report 1, Shulman and Lezotte, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Speeches, ca. 1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Analyzing Medical Inquiry Processes," Elstein, Spafka, Shulman, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Pedagogische Forschung - Versuch Einer Neufassung," Shulman, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Psychology of School Subjects: A Premature Obituary?" Shulman, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Medical Judgment Symposium, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Medical Judgment Conference, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Medical Judgment Conference, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Research on Teaching: Observations and Critiques," Shulman, [ca. 1975] (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "Evaluation of Problem Solving," Shulman [1975] (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Studies of Problem Solving, Judgment, and Decision Making: Implications for Educational Research," Shulman and Elstein [1975] (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "Strategies for Research on Personality Measures in Medical Education," Shulman and Elstein [ca. 1975] (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "An Analysis of Medical Inquiry Processes," 1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "An Analysis of Medical Inquiry Processes," Chapter Thirteen, revisions [ca. 1976] (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "Psychology and Mathematics Education Revisited," Shulman, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Edmonton, Alberta, May 5, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Detroit keynote address, May 14, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - ASPIN - AAMC Summer workshop, July 17-23, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "Lee Shulman Interviews Joseph Schwab," [ca. 1977] (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - OMERAD (Office of Medical Education Research and Development), 1977-1981 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "Characteristics of the Clinical Problem-Solving Model and Its Relevence to Education," Elstein, Shulman, Vinsonhaler, Wagner, Bader, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - "Investigations of Mathematics Teaching: A Perspective and Critique," Shulman, n.d. [June 1978] (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Book review: "Learning Theory and Teaching Methods: Going Steady No Longer," Lee Shulman, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Test Design," Shulman, [ca. 1978] (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Cincinnati, May 19, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "Recent Developments in the Study of Teaching," Shulman, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Papers in Preparation (unlikely completion!!), 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Training Program in Clinical Decision Making and Information Processes, Training Grant Application, ca. 1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Reflections on Individual Differences in the Study of Teaching," Shulman, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "Levels of Context in Teaching [?]," Shulman, ca. 1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Jewish Educators Assembly, March 15-18, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - "Educational Psychology Returns to School," Shulman [ca. 1981] (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - "Disciplines of Inquiry in Education: An Overview," Shulman, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - "Commentary on the 1981 NSSE Yearbook," Shulman, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - "Autonomy and Obligation: The Remote Control of Teaching," Shulman, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Cleveland Conference, December 2-3, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - "The Quality of Undergraduate Curriculum for Future Teachers," Shulman, Sykes, Ringstaff, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Bloom Conference: The Individual, The Environment & Education (3/1-3/84) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - "A Perspective on Effective Schools," Shulman, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - "The Practical and the Eclectic: A Deliberation on Teaching and Educational Research," Shulman, ca. 1984 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - "Psychology and the Limitations of Individual Rationality: Implications for the Study of Reasoning and Civility," Shulman and Carey, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - "On Teaching Problem Solving and and Problems of Teaching," Shulman, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Notes: "Overviews of Research Programs for Teaching," [ca. 1984-1985] (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - "Those Who Understand: Knowledge Growth in Teaching," Shulman, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "Educating Teachers: A Vision for the Future," Shulman, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "A Course of Treatment: Teaching and Medicine," Shulman, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "The Study of Knowledge in Teaching," Shulman, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "What do Teachers need to Know?" Shulman, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "Pedagogical Content Knowledge in Social Studies," Gudmundsdottir and Shulman, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "Current Research in the Psychology of Learning and Teaching," Shulman and Ringstaff, [ca. 1986] (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "A National Board for Teaching? In Search of a Bold Standard," Shulman and Sykes, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "Knowledge and Teaching: Foundations of the New Reform," Shulman, ca. 1986 (with "Further Comment," 1987) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "'150 Different Ways' of Knowing: Representations of Knowledge in Teaching," Wilson, Shulman, Richert, 1986/87 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - "Teaching Alone, Learning Together: Needed Agendas for the New Reforms," Shulman, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - "The Wisdom of Practice: Managing Complexity in Medicine and Teaching," Shulman, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - "Assessing Content and Process: Challenges for the New Assessments," Shulman address, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - "Assessment for Teaching: An Initiative for the Profession," Shulman, ca. 1987 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - "Shulman on National Certification," Shulman interview, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Lee Shulman's speech notes: Lee presenting Distinguished Lecture Notes, ATE Houston, February 15-17, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - "The Improvement of Teaching: A Cross-Occupational View," for Prospectus for NSSE Yearbook, 1987, Shulman and Sykes (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - "Learning to Teach," Shulman, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Spring Hill Conference, supporting documents, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - "Toward Alternative Assessments of Teaching: A Report of a Work in Progress," Shulman, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Lee Shulman's speech notes: AACTE, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "The Paradox of Teacher Assessment," Shulman, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - "The Dangers of Dichotomous Thinking," Shulman (evaluation of Schon's ideas), 1988 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "On Assessment of Teaching: Conversation with Shulman," Brandt, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - "A Union of Insufficiencies: Strategies for Teacher Assessment in a Period of Educational Reform," Shulman, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - "Learning for Teaching," Shulman, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "Case Notes: What is a Case?" (includes "Acceleration and Reflection in the Role of the Teacher," Shulman, 1988) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - "Toward a Pedagogy of Substance," Shulman, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "Teachers of Substance: Subject Matter Knowledge for Teaching," Grossman, Wilson, Shulman, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Lee Shulman's speech notes: 2nd Annual Anna Funk Lockey Lecture, Millersville University Project, April 12, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "Effective and Responsible Teaching," University of Fribourg, Sept. 1990 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - "Medical Problem Solving": Elstein, Shulman, Sprafka, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - "The Self-Fulfilling Prophecy: Its Genesis and Development in American Education," Wineburg and Shulman, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - "Reconnecting Foundations to the Substance of Teacher Education," Shulman, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - "Aristotle Had it Right: On Knowledge and Pedagogy," Shulman, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - "Pedagogical Ways of Knowing," Shulman Keynote address, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - "Ways of Seeing, Ways of Knowing: Ways of Teaching, Ways of Learning about Teaching," Shulman, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Amarel Memorial Lecture: presentation to the Holmes Group, January 1991 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - "Teaching Excellence in the University," prepared for panel discussion May 2, 1991, Stanford University (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - "Joseph Jackson Schwab (1909-1988)," Essay written for the University of Chicago Press Centennial Volume 1991 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - "Research on Teaching: A Historical and Personal Perspective," Shulman, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - "Intellectual Honesty," presented at AACTE Meeting, March 1992 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - "On Research on Teaching: A Conversation with Lee Shulman," 1992 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - "Toward a Pedagogy of Cases," January 1992 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - "Merging Content Knowledge and Pedagogy," 1992 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - "Interview with Lee S. Shulman," by Gudmunsdottir, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - "Renewing the Pedagogy of Teacher Ed: Impact of Subject-Specific Conceptions of Teaching," July 1992 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - "Displaying Teaching to a Community of Peers," 1993 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Lee Shulman's conclusion to "Detachment and Concern," 1993 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Valuing Teacher Knowledge," November 1993 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "Teaching as Community Property," 1993 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "Knowing, Believing, and the Teaching of English," Grossman and Shulman, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Speech - Math significance, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Toward Greater Excellence in Teaching at Stanford," Final Report to the C-AAA, April 1995 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "The Pedagogical Colloquium: Three Models," May 1995 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "Communities of Learners & Communities of Teachers," Mandel Institute Lecture, November 1995 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Notes for the Maatsch Lecture, MSU 1/96 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "The Comparative Psychology of School Subjects," Shulman and Quinlan, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - "Just in Case: Reflections on Learning from Experience," [ca. 1996] (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - "Biographical and Representative Published Materials," Shulman, 1996 [used for Carnegie Foundation application] (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - "Professional Development: Learning from Experience," 1997 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - AAHE Pedagogical Colloquim, February 1997 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - International Teacher Preparation & Professional Development Conf., July 1997 (Bellagio, Italy) (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - "Professing the Liberal Arts," 1997 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Speech at AFT National Higher Educational Issues Conference, April 1998 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - "Theory, Practice, and the Education of Professions," 1998 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Forward for the London Volume (What Kind of University?), 1998 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - "Teaching and Teacher Education Among the Professions," Hunt Lecture for the AACTE New Orleans 50yh Annual Meeting, February 1998 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - "Teacher Portfolios: A Theoretical Activity," 1998 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Foreward to George Hillocks' "Ways of Thinking,Ways of Teaching," 1998 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - "Course Anatomy: The Dissection and Analysis of Knowledge through Teaching," September 1998 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Foreward to "Teaching as a Learning Profession: Handbook," 1998 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - "Fostering a Scholarship of Teaching and Learning," Louise McBee lecture, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Introduction to "The Elementary School Journal," Phillips and Shulman, [ca. 1998] (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Foreward to "Knowing & Teaching Elementary Math," Spring 1999 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Foreward to "Private Power for the Public Good," 1999 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - "The Scholarship of Teaching: New Elaborations, New Developments," Hutchings and Shulman, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - "Taking Learning Seriously," 1999 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - "Memory and Experience," October 5, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Chinese Delegation USA visit, March 2000 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - "From Minsk to Pinsk: Why A Scholarship of Teaching and Learning," 2000 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Conclusion to "Opening Lines, Approaches to SOTL," 2000 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "Report of the President of the Foundation," June 2000 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "Teacher Development: Roles of Domain Expertise and Pedagogical Knowledge," 2000 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "Appreciating Good Teaching," interview by Carol Tell, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "Lamarck's Revenge," Arizona State Spring Symposium Lecture, March 2001 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Interview with Lee Shulman (Michigan State University New Educator), 2001 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - "Truth and Consequences? Inquiry and Policy in Research on Teacher Education," 2002 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Beth Am Presentation with Rabbi Joey Feldman, February 2002 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - AAHE: Taxonomic Trek, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - AAHE: Building a Field, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - "Toward Expert Thinking," Fall 2002 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - "Making Differences: A Table of Learning," 2002 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Fox Festschrift, 2003 ("Visions of Educational Leadership: Sustaining the Legacy of Seymour Fox") (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - "The Scholarship of Teaching in Higher Education," 2003 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - "Forgive and Remember," 2003 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - "Visions of the Possible," 2004 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Foreward to "Count Me In!" 2004 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - "Fostering Communities of Teachers as Learners: Disciplinary Perspectives," Shulman and Sherin, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - "How and What Teachers Learn: A Shifting Perspective," Shulman and Shulman, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - "If Not Now, When? The Timeliness of Scholarship of the Education of Engineers," 2005 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - "Pedagogies of Uncertainty," 2005 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - "Signature Pedagogies in the Professions," 2005 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - "Teacher Education Does Not Exist," 2005 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Foreward to "The Advancement of Learning," September 2005 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - "Classification's Complexities," 2005 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - "Seek Simplicity…and Distrust It," 2005 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - "To Dignify the Profession of Teaching: The Carnegie Foundation Celebrates 100 Years," 2005 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - "From Hermeneutic to Homiletic: The Professional Formation of Clergy," 2006 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - "A Conversation with Lee Shulman - Signature Pedagogies for Teacher Education," interview by Beverly Falk, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - "Reclaiming Education's Doctorates: A Critique and a Proposal," 2006 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - "Growing Concerns," interview of Lee Shulman, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - "More Than Competition," 2006 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - "This I Believe - Just Like Pastrami," NPR segment, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - "The Impossible Fullness of the Empty Classroom: A Letter of Appreciation," 2007 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Foreward to "A Brief History of Student Learning Assessment," Schneider and Shulman, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - "Good Teaching," 2007 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - "Counting and Recounting: Assessment and the Quest for Accountability," 2007 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - "Practical Wisdom in the Service of Professional Practice," 2007 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - "Where Genius Can Thrive," draft paper for International Conference, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Foreward to "Imagery in Teaching and Learning," n.d. (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - "Research Program to Develop New Procedures for the Assessment of Teachers," Shulman, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - "Sources and Standards for Teaching in California," in California Beginning Teacher Assessment and Support Project," Shulman, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - "Who's on First? Questions of Priority on Methods and Problems for Research in Teacher Education," Shulman, n.d. (with notes) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - "The Book or the Man: Education at the Crossroads," n.d. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "Relating Theory to Practice in Educational Research: A Working Paper," Shulman, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - "Educational Theory and Research," Shulman, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - "Paradigms and Research Programs in the Study of Teaching," n.d. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - "Research on Teaching in the Arts: Review, Analysis, Critique," Shulman, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "Research on Teaching: The Missing Link in Curriculum Implementation," Shulman, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - "Adapting the Teaching-Learning Process to redefined Goals," Shulman, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "Learning and Teaching in Higher Education," Shulman, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - "Learning: An Educational and Psychological Perspective," Shulman, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - "Some Aspects of Perception," [Lee Shulman?], n.d. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - "Inquiry Process," Chapter 1, Shulman, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - "The Problem of Discovery: Conference in Retrospect," Chapter XV, Keisler and Shulman, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Lee Shulman transcript for Claremont Conference talk, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Notes for Speeches; Research on teaching, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Speeches: cases (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Notes for Van Leer Lecture, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - speech/talk notes, [ca. 1999] (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - speech/talk notes, [ca. 1999-2000] (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - speech/talk notes, [ca. 1999-2000] (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - speech/talk notes, [ca. 1999-2000] (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - speech/talk notes, [ca. 2000] (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - speech/talk notes, [ca. 2000-2002] (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - speech/talk notes, [ca. 2001-2002] (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - speech/talk notes, [ca. 2002] (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - speech/talk notes, [ca. 2002] (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - speech/talk notes, [ca. 2002-2003] (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - speech/talk notes, [ca. 2002-2004] (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - speech/talk notes, [ca. 2004] (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - speech/talk notes, [ca. 2004-2006] (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - speech/talk notes, [ca. 2005-2006] (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - speech/talk notes, [ca. 2005-2006] (Box 11, Folder 6)
- PAPERS BY OTHERS, Series 3
  - "Teacher Decision Making in a Computer Simulated Classroom," Fagal, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lee Cronbach papers, ca. 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Creating a Methodology," Clift, Angus, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Science Group: Content and Process of Biology," Baxter, Richert, Saylor, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Role of Prior Subject Matter Knowledge in Learning to Teach Social Studies," Gudmundsdottir, Carey, Wilson, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Conceptual Change Learning and Student Processing of Science Texts," Kathleen Roth, 1985. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "English Major to English Teacher…," Grossman, Reynolds, Ringstaff, Sykes, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "A Comparison of Professional Examinations," Lareau, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Teacher Knowledge and Structuring Content in Mathematics," Steinberg, Haymore, Marks, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, University of Pittsburgh (Ohlsson, Voss, Post, Leinhardt, Greene), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Teaching Science," Anderson and Smith, 1985 (with Lee Shulman's notes) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bernard Gifford Papers, ca. 1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)